制作人：gemini0421  来源：人人影视
{\fad(500,500)\bord0\shad0\fscx11\fscy14\p1\c&HCE8F00&\t(45,50,1,\fry360)\move(74,198,62,226,45,50)}m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
{\fad(500,500)\bord0\shad0\fscx11\fscy14\p1\c&HF6DBA1&\t(45,50,1,\fry360)\move(74,198,62,226,45,50)}m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
{\fad(500,500)\bord0\shad0\fscx15\fscy18\p1\1a&H3D&\c&HFFFFFF&\blur10\move(64,188,51,218,45,50)}m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
(73,192,361,228)\move(16,210,205,210,0,500)\t(4500,5000,1,\frx1080)}翻译：大卫熊  Silence  点点点  欧阳  胖兔纯
(73,192,361,228)\move(16,210,205,210,0,500)\t(4500,5000,1,\frx1080)}翻译：王大可  圈圈  H小欠  冰蓝  我才是怪蜀黎
(73,192,361,228)\move(-40,210,205,210,0,500)\t(4500,5000,1,\frx1080)}时间轴：子衿  JimmyBeck    校对：米小勒  大卫熊
(73,192,361,228)\move(-40,210,200,210,0,500)\t(4500,5000,1,\frx1080)}后期：瓜瓜     总监：米小勒
{\fs20\3c&HFFFFFF&\fs36\fscx1450\alpha&H9F&\c&H000000&\bord1\shad0\clip(71,192,75,230)\t(0,500,1,\clip(73,192,361,228)\t(20000,20500,1,\clip(71,192,75,230)))\pos(206,229)}■
漫威公司出品
神盾局特工
第一季 第八集
在古代  人们相信
In ancient times, people believed
天堂满是众神  怪兽和魔法世界
the heavens were filled with gods and monsters and magical worlds.
随着时间的推移
Then, as time passed,
那些信仰变成了神话和传说
those beliefs faded into myth and folklore.
但现在我们知道故事是真的
But now we know the stories were true.
像阿斯加德这样的世界是存在的
Other worlds, with names like Asgard, exist.
像托尔这样曾被敬为神的人物
And beings once revered as gods, like Thor,
回到地球  留给我们更多的疑问
have returned, leaving us with more questions and...
一大堆烂摊子留待我们清理
An enormous mess to clean up.
别说我没给过你东西
Don't say I never gave you anything.
英国伦敦
格林威治大学
还得逐一在小石头上  检测外星的
Checking for alien spectrographic signatures
光谱特征径迹
one teeny rock at a time.
这是必要的预防措施
Necessary precaution.
我们可不想让外星物件被坏人拿到
We don't want anything alien getting in the wrong hands.
即便如此  这工作简单的连猴子都可以完成啊
Still, this is definitely the type of work a monkey could easily do.
你就是我们的小猴子
You're our little monkey.
妈妈&爸爸来电
别那样看着我
Don't give me that look.
我准备好了  自然会接电话
I'll talk to them when I talk to them.
接谁的电话
Talk to who?
妈妈和爸爸
Mum and dad.
他们想知道...
They want explanations and answers for...
有关这些东西的解释
Well, all this.
但是我没法回答他们
But I don't have any answers.
更重要的是  自从我被感染后
And, more importantly, I haven't talked to them
还没跟他们谈过
since I was ill.
如果他们知道了  他们会更害怕
And if they knew that, they'd be even more terrified.
所以  你知道的
So, you know...
何必浪费时间呢
...why waste any of our time, really?
你们觉得这是陈年旧事
You guys may think it's old news,
其实它...对每个人来说都是新闻
but it's new...news to everybody else.
阿斯加德人是来自另一个星球的外星人
So, Asgardians are aliens from another planet
千年之前曾拜访过我们
that visited us thousands of years ago?
可能还要更早
Or more.
因为我们不了解外星人
And because we couldn't understand aliens,
我们就以为他们是神
we thought they were gods?
北欧神话就是这么诞生的
That's where our Norse mythology comes from.
太疯狂了
That's too crazy.
你们认为其他神也是外星人吗
Do you think other deities are aliens, too?
毗湿奴[印度教主神之一]肯定是  对吧
Vishnu for sure, right?
哪怕一次也好
You know, it'd be nice if, for once,
真希望托尔和他的人能把
Thor and his people sent down
"搞破坏后自己清理"之神派下来
the god of cleaning up after yourself.
他们也许有个魔法扫帚之类的
They probably have a magic broom for this kind of thing.
真希望他们把外星飞船留下
I just wish they'd left their alien ship behind.
好让我们把那个也清理吗
So we can clean that up, too?
好让我们进去  看看里面
So we could go inside, take a peek under the hood,
或许兜兜风什么的
maybe take it for a spin.
拜托  难道你要告诉我
Come on, you're telling me
开外星飞船不在你的遗愿清单上吗
piloting an alien ship isn't on your bucket list?
我印象中
I can't think of a single time
外星人物件落到人类手中都没有好下场
when anything alien in human hands ended well.
我倒是不介意让托尔的东西"落到我手中"
Wouldn't mind getting my human hands on Thor.
他是梦幻般的存在
He's so dreamy.
是的  他虽说是挺英俊的  但...
Sure, he's handsome, but --
不  他的确是梦幻般的存在
No. He's dreamy.
菲兹  那是...
Fitz, is that, um --
肯定不是这个星球来的
Definitely not from here.
应该是飞船的一部分  你在干什么
Another piece of the ship. What are you doing?
眼不见...
Out of sight...
...心不烦
...out of mind.
这才是我们来的目的
That's why we're here.
确保一切在控制之下
Keep everything under control.
挪威
特莱马卡国家公园
-谁会干这种事  -谁知道呢
- Now, who would do something like that? - Who knows.
宝贝  看
Baby, look.
"水之南  山之北"
"South of the water, north of the hill..."
"一圈石头"
"...A halo of stones" --
"环绕大树"
"Protect the tree still."
雅各布  是它吗
Jakob, is this it?
我们应该去看看
We should check that out.
终于找到了
Finally, after all this time.
等不及告诉其他人了
I can't wait to tell the others.
我说过这是真的...
I told you it was real...
而且我会找到的
And that I would find it.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
不要排斥你感觉到的东西
What you're feeling, don't fight it.
那种愤怒  已经存在于你体内了
That rage, it's already inside of you.
不要害怕  不要隐藏它的力量
Don't be afraid of it. Don't hide from its power.
接纳它
Embrace it.
Embrace it!
天呐  你们做了什么
God! What have you done?
神盾局特工
第一季 第八集
需要的话你可以让我爬
I can climb it if you want.
但要跟我说怎么用这些...小玩意
Just talk me through what to do with the...doodads.
也就15英尺[4.6米]高
Yeah, it's only about 15 feet.
我没事  我...
I'll be fine. I'm --
只是从那次差点摔死之后
I'm just a bit more wary about the height thing
我就对高度比较谨慎
since falling to certain death.
你很害怕
You're afraid.
在发抖是吗
Hmm? Shaken up?
很正常
It's normal.
但有的感觉就是
But some feelings will take over
你越去想就会越强烈
if you dwell on them.
特别是恐惧
Especially fear.
现在  一直看前面
Now, keep your eyes ahead.
注意力集中到你最想做的事情上
Focus on what you like to do best.
好的
Yep.
不是掉下去
Not falling.
不是  是调查
No, research.
你是一个科学家  你马上就能解决难题
You're a scientist. You like to figure things out.
是的  用我的小玩意
Yes. With my doodads.
我很好奇
I'm curious.
不管树上的东西是什么
Whatever was up in these trees
都已经在那里几个世纪了  是吗
had to be there for centuries, right?
至少上千年
At least a millennium.
放射性碳14记录了其中有一些树
Radiocarbon-14 dates some of these trees
有九千年了
at 9,000 years old.
听起来不可能啊  难道树是围着它生长的吗
That sounds impossible. Think the tree grew around it?
我得先查查年轮
I'd have to check the dendrochronology first
才能确定
to know for certain. Uh-huh.
当然  但是  挪威云杉
Of course. But, I mean, the Norway spruce
是生长相当快的松柏科植物
is a rather fast-growing coniferous,
而且我知道你会骗我再爬高点
and I know you're trying to trick me into going up,
不管怎么说我会往上爬  所以
but I'm going up anyway, so...
如果你掉下来了我会接住你的
I'll catch you if you fall.
尖叫  她眼里还有很多仇恨
Screaming, and so much hate in her eyes.
你说她还拿着一根银棒
And you said she had a silver stick?
也可能是钢的  我  我不知道
Steel, maybe. I-I don't know.
上面  还有图案
It, uh, had decorations on it.
你能形容一下或是画下来吗
Could you describe or draw them?
我没仔细看  我  我就逃了
I didn't get a good look. I I just ran.
谁会做这么邪恶的事
Who would do something so evil?
很遗憾你失去了同事
I'm sorry for your loss.
结果:阳性
检测到外星物质
这里面的东西
Oh, um, whatever was in here
肯定不是这个世界上的
was definitely not from this world.
菲兹  你收到了吗
Fitz, you getting this?
这不是奇塔瑞的  是吧
It's not Chitauri, is it?
不不不  别担心
No, no, no. Don't worry.
这不是病毒威胁
This isn't another viral threat.
等一下
Um, hang on.
光谱特征符合资料上的...
Spectrographic signatures match readings from...
雷神托尔之锤
Thor's hammer.
西蒙斯  树里面的东西来自阿斯加德
Simmons, whatever was in that tree is Asgardian.
我  我能看到嵌入的印记
I-I can see an imprint of what was embedded.
三维立体复位扫描
Scanning for three-dimensional restoration.
好了告诉我
Tell me when.
好了
When.
看上去像是根手杖或者枝条
Um, looks like a staff or a rod.
精心制作  完美雕刻
Well crafted. Engraved.
我转换一下  做一个3D模型
I'll convert it, print a 3-d model.
这片森林是自然保护区
This forest is a protected reserve.
他们以为他们是谁啊
I mean, who do they think they are?
还有别的什么细节吗
Anything else? Details?
有没有能帮我们找到那些人
Anything that might help us to find these people
或是他们可能藏在哪里的线索
or where they might be hiding?
长官  他们看上去并没有躲
Sir, doesn't look like they're hiding.
奥斯陆[挪威首都]街区突发暴力事件
现在发到你手机上
Sending to your devices now.
奥斯陆街区突发暴力事件
...造成20人受伤  3人生命垂危
...leaving 20 injured, 3 in critical condition.
报道显示这十余人组成的队伍
Reports indicate that the group of about a dozen
奥斯陆出现暴力事件
据称疑犯仍未被捕
由这一男一女牵头
was led by this man and woman,
尽管还不清楚他们的动机
and though their motive was unclear,
但他们所要传递的信息
their message was hauntingly spelled out
已经留在了奥斯陆的街头
on the streets of Oslo.
看来我们知道他们的身份了
Well, I guess we know who they think they are.
我们是神
雅各布・奈斯特龙  佩特拉・拉尔森
雅各布・奈斯特龙  三十岁
Jakob Nystrom, 30.
他的女朋友  佩特拉・拉尔森
Girlfriend, Petra Larsen.
一个挪威异教徒组织的领袖
Leaders of a Norse paganist hate group.
多亏了格林威治发生的事
And their numbers are growing,
和互联网
thanks to what happened in Greenwich
他们组织的人数还在增长
and thanks to the internet.
没错  就是互联网  她说得真讽刺啊
Yay, internet, she said sarcastically.
挪威异教徒
Norse paganist?
沉迷于与挪威神话也就是阿斯加德的故事
Obsessed with anything derived from norse mythology --
相关的一切
stories of Asgard.
现在我们要对付的是一件武器
And now a weapon.
只能扫描到其一侧
The scan only accounted for one side.
树上损伤太严重了  难以完全复制
Too much damage to the tree for complete reproduction.
但看看这里  很明显两端都有损伤
But see here -- it's clearly broken on both ends.
也就是说还有其他几部分吗
So there are more pieces?
对  至少还有两部分
Yeah. Two at least.
就是说这对情侣很有可能在找其他几部分
Which means Sid and Nancy may be looking for a complete set.
雅各布・奈斯特龙  佩特拉・拉尔森
这是什么图案  阿斯加德的符号
The markings? Asgardian symbolism.
仅凭我们有限的知识很难进行翻译
Hard to translate with our limited knowledge.
你应该把你那雷神朋友喊过来
You should give your buddy the god of thunder a shout.
他从他的锤子那里得到力量  对吧
He gets his power from his hammer, right?
或许这是他锤子上的螺丝呢
What if this is his nail to the hammer?
我已经找过了
I already did.
弗瑞局长跟我说找不到他
Director Fury told me he's off the grid.
即使他有手机  我们也没他的号码
And if he has a cellphone, we don't have the number.
神盾局主要着手于寻找
S.H.I.E.L.D.'s investigation are on the trail
奈斯特龙和他的信众
of Nystrom and his followers.
我们负责辨认出目标
We're charged with identifying the object
并抢先一步找到其他几块
and finding any other pieces before they do.
看来他们有些优势
They seem to have some advantage.
他们在150平方公里的挪威森林里
They found this thing in 150 square kilometers
找到这东西
of norwegian forest.
各位  或许是它用魔法在召唤他们呢
Guys. What if it called to them with magic?
召唤他们吗
Called to them.
我们知道这是阿斯加德的东西
We know it's Asgardian,
所以这方面有很多我们不知道的法则
so the rules are a little bendy here.
我们只不过还没弄明白一些问题
Just because we don't understand something yet
这不意味着我们要倒退回中世纪
doesn't mean we should regress back to the dark ages,
尽说些魔法和神话什么的
talking of magic and fairy tales.
其实  我们正要这么做
Actually, that's exactly what we're going to do.
-你说什么  -真的吗
- Excuse me? - Really?
当我们在新墨西哥找到那锤子的时候
When we first found the hammer in New Mexico,
我请教了一个在全球挪威神话研究方面
I consulted one of the world's leading experts
领头的专家
on Norse Mythology --
埃利奥特・兰道夫
Elliot Randolph,
在塞维尔的一所大学当教授
a professor at a university in Seville.
我们马上就去找他
We'll leave immediately.
或许他可以告诉我们更多这些图案的信息
Maybe he can tell us more about these markings.
西班牙  塞维尔
有一点必须纠正  埃琳娜
Well, one must adapt, Elena.
最近发生的事让我们改观了
Recent events have thrown us all for a loop.
我一直以为我在教挪威神话
I thought I was teaching Norse Mythology.
其实不然  结果证明我是一个历史学教授
No, turns out I'm a history professor.
就是说  你不打算更改我的分数吗
So, you're not going to change my grade?
不  我会给你一个星期去重写
No. I will give you a week to rewrite it.
我想  一般而言
I think, in general,
应多一点历史描述  少一点评价
Little more history, less lit crit.
但我还是希望今晚我们可以共进晚餐
But I do hope we're still on for dinner tonight.
我列了一个书籍的清单
I've included a list of books there
这些书或许能帮得到你
that might help you.
再见
I'll see you later.
兰道夫教授
Professor Randolph.
科尔森特工  请进  请进
Agent coulson. Come in, come in.
沃特菲尔德44
Waterfield 44.
14k金的笔尖嵌上珍珠母
14-karat-gold nib with mother-of-pearl inlay.
你挺有眼光的嘛
That's quite an eye you've got.
我不知道你还是个收藏家
I didn't know you were a collector.
政府付的钱  我不算是个收藏家
On a government salary, not quite.
我猜你们在伦敦的地上找到些什么
Well, I'm assuming you found something on the ground in London.
在挪威的树里面找到的
In a tree in Norway.
不幸的是
And, unfortunately,
不是我们找到它的
We weren't the ones who found it.
这是个3D模型
It's a 3-D model.
太不可思议了
Oh, that is amazing.
基于这些如尼文
Now, based on these runes,
我得说这是狂暴战士手杖的一部分
I'd say I'm looking at a piece of the berserker staff.
我们来看一看
Let's have a look.
没错  神话故事要追溯到十二世纪晚期
Yeah, the myth dates back to the late 12th century.
是关于一名来自阿斯加德的强大勇士的
It's all about a powerful warrior from Asgard.
这里
Here.
一名狂暴战士军队的士兵
A soldier in the berserker army.
狂暴战士军队
Berserker army?
是的
Oh, yeah.
一支强大的军队
A powerful army.
曾经是一支残暴的军队
Fierce army it was.
狂暴战士们像愤怒的野兽一样战斗
Berserkers battled like raging beasts,
摧毁他们道路上的一切
destroying everything in their path.
一名狂暴战士拥有二十名勇士的力量
A single berserker had the strength of 20 warriors.
那么无论谁持有手杖就拥有了超人类的力量
So whoever wielded the staff got superhuman strength?
用它战斗会将勇士置于
Fighting with it put the warrior
一种无法控制的愤怒状态
into a state of uncontrollable rage.
手杖拥有一种非常强大的魔法
The staff contained a very powerful magic.
或者一种我们还未发现的科学特性
Or a scientific attribute we've yet to discover.
拥有分析性的头脑并且笑靥如花
Analytically minded and pretty as a peach.
你是在说传说中的勇士吗
The warrior in the story.
在传说中  他来到地球上是为了战斗
Well, in the story, he came to earth to fight,
结果却坠入了爱河
but he ended up falling in love.
爱上了谁
With whom?
爱上了地球上的生活
With life on earth.
通了人性
Humanity.
他爱得如此之深
He fell so much in love
以至于当他的军队返回阿斯加德的时候
that when his army returned to Asgard,
他留了下来
he stayed behind.
手杖怎么样了
What happened to the staff?
他不想让它的黑暗魔法
Well, he didn't want its dark magic
落入错误的人之手
falling into the wrong hands,
所以他把手杖断成三部分
so he broke it into three pieces
每一部分藏在了不同的地方
and hid each one in a different location.
手稿上不会正好有说
The manuscript wouldn't happen to say
他把它们藏在了哪里对吧
where he hid them, would it?
实际上  有说
Actually, it does.
在三首诗里
In three verses.
请诸位铭记在心这些诗意抽象
Now, let's all bear in mind these are poetic abstracts
是从失传已久的古文字里面来的
from long-lost ancient texts.
有一首是关于一棵树
So, there is one about a tree,
看起来他们已经找到了
which they've found, it seems.
另一首  "河流以东  烈日当空
Another is, "East of the river, sun overhead,
与逝去之人的尸骨同埋于土壤中"
buried in earth with the bones of the dead."
有点毛骨悚然  不是吗
That's a bit macabre, isn't it?
还有另外一首
There's another here.
这一首甚至连韵脚都没有
Well, this one doesn't even have a rhyme.
不过它的主旨是  "接近上帝"
But the gist of it is "Close to god."
那可以是指任何东西  不是吗
That could be anything, couldn't it?
也可能什么都不指
It could also mean nothing.
我还希望能够少一些暗喻
I was hoping for less metaphor,
多一些经纬度之类的
more longitude and latitude.
我想  沿着维京海盗袭击路线搜寻
Well, I mean, it does stand to reason
显然是合乎情理的  不是吗
to search near Viking raid routes, doesn't it?
近来在加拿大沿海一带的巴芬岛
Now, there have been some recent interesting findings
有些关于挪威人遗迹的有趣的发现
of Norse relics on Baffin Island off the coast of Canada.
可谓史前古器物中的无价之宝
Yeah, virtual treasure trove of new artifacts.
那么我们就从那里入手  谢谢你  教授
We'll start there, then. Thank you, professor.
你知道巴芬岛上有一座托尔峰吗
Did you know there's Mount Thor on Baffin Island?
不知道
I did not.
你知道托尔峰上没有什么吗
Do you know what's not on Mount Thor?
和阿斯加德有半点联系的东西都没有
Anything Asgardian at all.
我们在那里的特工什么都没有找到
Our agents on the ground haven't found a thing.
你这里怎么样
What about you?
奈斯特龙深度网络中的留言板上
Nystrom's deep-web message boards
正有一群疯子在叽叽喳喳
are just abuzz with psychos.
他们坚信自己将升仙为
They believe they're gonna ascend
死亡与毁灭之神
to be the gods of destruction and death.
都是些鸟人  长官
People suck, sir.
这就是你的进展吗  "都是些鸟人"
That's your progress? "People suck"?
这些人确实很烂
These people do.
另外他们还喋喋不休有关进行地下行动
And there's also chatter about going underground.
可能是指隐姓埋名或者...
Could mean going incognito or...
或者寻找手杖的下一部分
Or searching for the next piece.
兰道夫说要沿着维京人的路线搜索
Randolph said to check viking routes.
找到其它的了吗
Find any others?
在俄罗斯境内的伏尔加河沿岸有些遗址
There's some sites along the Volga River in Russia,
基辅也有一些  更奇怪的是  这里也有
Some in Kiev, and, weirdly, here.
塞维尔
在西班牙的塞维尔吗
In Seville, Spain?
可能性比较小
It's a long shot,
但维京人曾两次侵占过塞维尔
but vikings sacked Seville twice.
我们找到一个有可能存放维京遗物的地点
We found one promising location with viking relics --
艾尔德维诺尼诺
El Divino Nino.
一个建立在公元八世纪地穴废墟上的教堂
A church built on the ruins of an 8th-century crypt
而在那之前是个公元前206年的罗马遗址
built on Roman ruins from 206 B.C.
河流的东边
East of a river.
还有许多的遗骨
And lots of bones.
看看我们能不能发现[挖出]点什么
Let's see what we can dig up.
听出我的双关语了吗
See what I did there?
这感觉一定不错
Must be nice --
能有规定的午休时间
have a mandatory nap time.
午休不是政府规定的
Siesta isn't mandatory.
气候炎热国家如西班牙等有午睡的习惯
但午睡确实是件美事
Just very pleasant.
你怎么样  沃德特工
How you doing, Agent Ward?
真希望我没长这么高
Wishing I was shorter.
暂时还没有发现
Nothing yet.
检测结果  无异常
我的仪器读数显示一切正常
All my readings are normal.
那你呢  斯凯  运气怎么样
What about you, Skye? Any luck?
幸运的是我的监管人员
I'm lucky my S.O. volunteered
主动提出搜索那条最阴森恐怖的走道
to take the super-creepy hallway
而把这间好不到哪去的地牢留给了我
instead of the slightly less-creepy dungeon-room place.
我没有发现
I got nothing.
抱歉  啥都没有
Sorry -- nada.
沃德  你的光谱仪检测出周围有异常
Ward, your spectrograph is reading something near you.
我什么都没看见
I don't see anything.
仪器显示就在你正前方
Well, it's right in front of you.
等等...不对  好吧...稍等
Oh, wait. No. Uh, okay, hold on.
它正在移动  西北方向
It's moving. Northwest.
我看到可疑人物了
Visual contact.
沃德  向左转
Ok Ward, turn left.
我可以解释这一切
I have a wonderful explanation.
你是想说碰巧撞见一些异常...
Ran into some unexpected com--
沃德  发生了什么事
Ward, what's happening?
他的仪器刚刚失去了联系
His device just went down.
-斯凯  你能...  -已经在路上了
- Skye, can you get... - Already on it.
沃德
Ward.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
格兰特  冷静点  求你了
Grant, calm down. Calm down, please.
冷静下来
Calm down.
手杖...被他拿走了
The staff -- he has it.
沃德有点不对劲
Something's wrong with Ward.
手杖也不见了  有人拿走了它
The staff's gone. Someone took it.
我也有一截
I have one, too.
他不会就这么凭空消失的
He can't just disappear.
他总要找个地方回到...
He'll have to turn up some...
地面
...where.
就是那里
There we go.
距小教堂南边一个街区的位置
A block south of the chapel.
教授
Professor.
我搞砸了
I screwed up.
-这么做真没必要  -很有必要
- This is ridiculous. - It's anything but.
沃德  你刚刚昏迷了
Ward, you passed out.
而且你现在的举止很不正常
And you were acting not right.
科尔森命令我给你做一个详细的全面检查
Coulson ordered me to give you a full work-up,
这就是我正在做的
and that's exactly what I'm doing.
在你失去知觉前
Um, before you lost consciousness,
你有没有产生幽闭恐惧症的感觉
were you feeling claustrophobic?
为什么这么问
Why?
她只是在排除恐惧发作的可能性
She's ruling out a panic attack.
我从不会感到恐惧  从来不会
I don't panic. Ever.
好的  排除这项
There we go. Ruled out.
你是触碰了手杖才这样的  是吗
Touching the staff caused it, right?
有任何残留的症状吗
Any residual effects?
你是否感受到身体内有异于寻常的力量
Are you exhibiting any extra s-strength?
不如我拿那家伙来试试
Why don't I find out on that guy?
不如我们还是别这么做比较好
Why don't we not do that?
在你昏迷之前
What's the last thing you remember
你记得的最后一件事是什么
before you lost consciousness?
这简直是浪费时间
This is a waste of time.
我们得尽快找到手杖
We need to find the staff.
你到底记得了什么
What exactly do you remember?
一些我很久都没有想起过的事
Something I hadn't thought about in a long time.
我们还是别问了
Why don't we leave it alone?
我是说  他刚把手臂抽出了...
Well, I mean, he just pulled his arm out of this --
安静
Quiet!
我想听他说什么
I want to hear this.
我的手下受伤了  手杖不见了
One of my men is hurt. The staff is gone.
我也不想那样
I didn't want any of that to happen.
那你想怎样
What did you want?
你想自己独享手杖的力量么
The staff's power for yourself?
根本不是那样
Nothing like that.
我只是想成为第一个研究它的人
You know, I just wanted to be the first to study it,
证明狂暴战士真的曾经来过这里
to prove that the Berserkers were actually here,
是历史的一部分
a part of history.
你试想一下那会怎样
You think about that.
我在想
Oh, I'm thinking about it.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你的心率在上升  肾上腺素分泌激增
Your heart rate's rising. Adrenaline's spiking.
你需要冷静下来  不能情绪激动
You need to calm down, not get worked up.
那段回忆  是有关你弟弟的么
The memory -- was it about your brother?
别说了
Drop it.
沃德  如果你需要宣泄一下情绪
Ward, if you need to get it out,
我可以和你
I am here --
谈谈么
Right. To talk.
因为你就只会谈谈  谈了又谈
Because that's what you do -- talk...and talk.
你都不会对自己的声音感到厌倦么
Don't you ever get tired of hearing your own voice?
沃德  别这样
Ward, stop.
这就说得通了
Well! This makes more sense.
沃德  你所经历的  现在这种感觉
Ward, what you're experiencing, this feeling --
是一种化学反应
It's chemistry.
希望如此
Hope so.
是的  他的促肾上腺皮质激素出现峰值
Yeah, spikes in his adrenocorticotropic hormone.
就像你听到的那些故事里讲的一样
It's like those stories you hear
一个母亲为了救自己的孩子抬起了一辆车
when a mother is able to lift a car to save her baby.
肾上腺素激增可以产生巨大的
An adrenaline surge can create a massive --
别说了
Stop talking!
治好它
Just fix it!
我也希望我能
I wish I could.
我们可以减轻部分症状
We can relieve some of the symptoms.
我会给你注射10毫升的苯二氮
I'm going to give you 10cc of benzodiazepine.
冷静小药丸  好主意
Chill pill. Good idea.
镇静剂  不可能
A sedative? Not gonna happen.
讲讲道理  看看你现在的样子
Yeah, well, be reasonable. Look how you're behaving.
如果给我注射了镇静剂
And if I'm sedated
然后我们碰上了那群"嗨翻"的疯子
and we cross paths with those juiced freaks,
那群掀翻车子  把人压扁的疯子
the ones who flip cars and smash people up,
你来解决掉他们么
are you gonna take them on?
你来保护我们么
Keep us safe?
还是要我再救西蒙斯一次
Or am I gonna have to save Simmons' ass...again?
那只是生物化学反应
That was just a biochemical reaction.
他不是那个意思
He didn't mean all that.
我懂
No, I know.
不用解释
No explanation necessary.
他们怎么找到它的  我完全没有头绪
How'd they find it? I have no idea how they found it.
他们也许有原始文本
They may have the original texts.
跟我没关系
I wasn't involved.
你知道么  这只是一个
You know, it was just a chance to uncover something
发掘神从天堂带来之物的机会
that the gods brought down from the heavens.
那是外星人带来的  从外太空
Aliens brought it. From space.
我曾经和外星人独处过
I've spent some one-on-one time with aliens before.
相处得并不融洽
Didn't work out too well.
所以这类案件对我来讲  很私人化
So cases like this are personal to me.
我只知道这些
That's all I know.
好好待着吧
Get comfortable.
帮帮我
Help me!
求你了  帮帮我
Please! Help me!
帮帮我
Help me!
求你了
Please!
沃德
Hey, Ward!
你应该更加小心
You should be more careful.
我没事  你呢
I'm fine. You?
我正在试图解决这个问题
I'm working it out.
你在猛击泄愤
You're punching things.
这是你最不需要做的事情了
The last thing you need is to punch things.
那你有别的好办法么
You got a better idea?
让我帮你吧
Let me help you.
我现在唯一需要的帮助就是
The only help I need is to stop those guys
在那些家伙再伤人之前阻止他们
before they hurt somebody else.
我们是新的秩序
We are the new order!
我们的世界正在被众神夺走
Our world is being taken by gods!
我们将要成为众神并把它夺回来
We will become gods and take it back!
这就是新的秩序
This is the new order!
你准备将权力夺回来了吗
Are you ready to take back the power?
神盾局移动行动小组
地点  审讯室
你有时间吗  长官
A moment, sir?
进来吧
Come on in.
我担心之前与那件武器的接触
I'm concerned that my exposure to that weapon
严重影响了我的工作能力
has compromised my ability to do my job.
继续说
Go on.
你知道我家史
You're familiar with my family history.
因显而易见的原因  我不会回想自己的童年
So, for obvious reasons, I don't think back to childhood.
从不
Ever.
有些事我很久以前就封存起来了
There are things I put away a long time ago.
封得严严实实
On lockdown.
因为要做好现在的工作  我必须专注  机智
Because to do this, I have to be focused, tactical.
我不能分心
I can't be distracted.
尤其不能被很久以前发生的一些事分心
Especially by things that happened a lifetime ago.
你的意思是摸了那件东西会释放某些记忆
You're saying touching the staff unlocked certain memories.
最痛苦的记忆
My worst memory.
我第一次感觉到...
The first time I felt...
仇恨
hate.
而且这种感觉挥之不去
And it won't go away.
我不信任我自己
I don't trust myself.
我在实验室里对斯凯和菲茨・西蒙斯发火...
The way I went off at Skye and Fitz-Simmons in the lab --
格兰特  你告诉我这些
Grant... you telling me this
让我感觉我可以信任你
makes me feel I can trust you.
可是他...
Him, on the other hand...
我无法让教授开口
I can't get the professor to talk.
你不是积压了些愤怒吗
You've got some rage built up.
现在是时候发泄一下了
Maybe it's time to let it out.
你得开口说实话
You need to start talking.
我知道的  都已经跟科尔森特工说了
I told Agent Coulson everything I know.
你在撒谎
You're lying.
告诉我那玩意对我做了什么
Tell me what that thing did to me
我怎样才能恢复
and how fix it.
我发誓我真的不知道
I swear I don't know.
那好吧
Okay, then.
你说得对
You were right.
他是阿斯加德人
He's Asgardian.
这是好事
Good thing.
否则那就太尴尬了
Otherwise, that would have been awfully embarrassing.
好吧  我很想知道
Okay, I have to know.
你是怎么发现的
How did you figure me out?
推理
Did the math.
第一  你不是我抓住的第一个阿斯加德人
One -- you're not the first Asgardian I've had in custody.
你们这种人不会因被抓而畏惧或者慌张
You guys don't flinch or panic in captivity.
第二  就凭教授那点工资
Two -- a Waterfield 44?
能买得起沃特菲尔德44号吗
On a lit professor's salary?
我看未必
I don't think so.
最后
And lastly,
如果我告诉别人我跟外星人
when I tell someone I've had some one-on-one time
独处过
with an alien,
一般人会比较好奇
they tend to be a little curious.
显然你比一般人更具洞察力  科尔森特工
Well, you're certainly more observant than most, Agent Coulson.
你就是那个留下的阿斯加德人对吧
So, you're the Asgardian warrior who stayed.
不要跟别人说  拜托了
Please don't tell anyone.
真是没想到啊
I had no clue.
你呢
Did you?
就在光天化日之下  一个真正阿斯加德人
Hidden in plain sight -- an actual Asgardian.
太厉害了
Brilliant.
你觉得他在地球上待了多久了
How long do you suppose he's been on our planet?
一千年  可能更久
A thousand years. Maybe more.
如果我们把他稍微割开一下
If we could just cut him open a little bit,
提取些组织样本  或者是体液
get some tissue samples, maybe some bodily fluids,
那就可以确定了
we could find out.
也可以直接问他啊  你个怪人
Or we could just ask him, weirdo.
这个比看历史频道过瘾多了
This is way, way better than the history channel.
这家伙经历过所有恐怖的事件
I mean, this guy has lived through all the scary stuff --
十字军东征  黑死病  迪斯科
the Crusades, the Black Death, disco.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
把审讯室的门封上
Sealing the interrogation-room door.
科尔森下的命令
Coulson's orders.
要把我关起来啊
Ah, locking me in.
更严密的牢房我都待过
Well, I've been in tighter spots.
这间屋子是由碳化硅涂层的
This room is made of a silicon carbide-coated
震金合金打造
vibranium alloy.
专门用来关你这种人
Meant for prisoners like yourself.
但你也在这里面
But you're in here, too.
那扇门终归还是得打开
And eventually, somebody will open that door.
我让他们打开才会打开
Not if I tell them not to.
这么说  神话就是你的自传
So, the myth is your autobiography.
不是我写的
I didn't write it.
我不想让人知道我的身份
I didn't want anyone to know about me.
可我管不住自己的嘴
Then I had to open my big mouth.
你是被俘虏了
Were you captured?
还是被严刑拷打
Tortured?
性欲
Horny.
1546年我和一名法国女孩相识
I met a French girl in 1546.
她喜欢听故事
Ah, she loved stories.
所以
So...
我给她讲了一个很棒的故事
I told her a great one.
告诉她关于留下来的那个阿斯加德人的事
All about the peaceful Asgardian warrior who stayed.
我怎么会知道
Now, how was I to know
她的牧师哥哥会将其记录下来
her brother the priest would write it all down
后来成了  我也不清楚  神话
and turn it into, I don't know, a thing?
你知道托尔吗
Do you know Thor?
当然  我耗费一生精力想要结识
Oh, sure, I spent all my days palling around
未来的阿斯加德之王
with the future king of Asgard.
我当然不认识托尔
No, I don't know Thor.
我是个石匠
I was a mason.
凿石头的
I broke rocks.
你根本无法想象
For thousands of years.
我凿了几千年的石头
If you can imagine that.
所以他们来征兵时
So when they came, asking for people to fight,
很自然地  我就参军了
Yes, of course I signed up.
我其实就是想到处走走
I think, really, I just wanted to travel.
但你有手杖
But you had the staff.
我讨厌那玩意
I hated that thing.
其他人沉溺于狂怒所带来的力量
Other guys loved all the power that comes with the rage.
但是我不为所动
No, I didn't like it at all.
看起来  你和我一样
And you don't, either, it seems.
那手杖对我做了什么
What did it do to me?
它能在你内心最阴暗的角落点一盏灯
It shines a light into your dark places.
不管你是人类  还是阿斯加德人
Doesn't matter if you're human, asgardian.
效果都一样
The effect is the same --
让人不舒服
Unpleasant.
"点一盏灯"  说了等于没说
"Shines a light." That's no explanation.
手杖由一种稀有金属锻造而成
It was forged from a rare metal
对任何持有者都起作用
and reacts to whoever is holding it.
或产生互通
Or interacts.
我大费周章
I went to such great lengths
就是为了不让手杖被发现
to make sure that the staff wasn't found.
不幸的是  传说被记录了下来
Unfortunately, since the myth was written down,
几千年来  有人不停地寻找手杖
people have been searching for it for centuries.
在他们拿到最后一截手杖前
I need your help to stop them
我需要你的帮助去阻止这些人
before they get the last piece of your staff.
可我现在是和平爱好者
Oh, I am a pacifist now.
而且你不希望自己的身份暴露
And you don't want to risk your identity being discovered.
听着  我不担心
Listen, I wouldn't worry too much
那些冲动的年轻人
about these angry youths.
他们总会冷静下来
They always calm down,
然后最终  衰老消逝
and eventually, they die of old age.
这就是地球上生命的可贵之处
And that is one of the pleasant aspects of life here.
万物变化无穷
Everything changes.
我来告诉你什么会变化
I'll tell you what's gonna change --
你的隐匿身份
Your anonymity...
除非你帮助我找到最后一截手杖
Unless you help up find the final piece of your staff.
你可能不认识托尔
You may not know Thor.
但我认识
But I do.
爱尔兰是我初来地球时的挚爱
My first love on this planet was Ireland.
那里有一座庙宇  那里的僧侣
There was a monastery, and the monks gave me
给了我舒睡的地方
a nice, warm place to sleep,
几碗汤
some soup,
还有一些热红酒
and some mulled wine.
"近神之地"
"Near god."
手杖所施加的效果
The effects of the staff.
是永久的吗
Are they permanent?
力量会慢慢消退
The strength wears off.
之后你会感到精疲力尽
You will feel exhausted afterwards.
需要睡眠
You'll need sleep.
那...
What about...
其他不良反应呢
the other effects?
你是说心底那阴暗而猛烈的痛
Oh, that dark, nasty ache in the pit of your stomach,
还有胸腔那股让你以为
the rage in your chest that makes you feel
心要爆炸的愤怒
as if your heart's about to explode?
人类会更难受些
It's worse on humans.
但过个几十年
But give it a few decades,
终会消退
and it'll wear off, too.
真是太好了
Great.
你觉得沃德的状况适合出外勤吗
Are you sure Ward's okay to go into the field?
他显然有点不在状态
He's not exactly acting like himself.
他知道这一点
But he knows it.
他没问题
He'll be fine.
我同意科尔森的意见
I'm with Coulson.
有段时间没来了  我想...
Well, it's been a while. I wonder --
是的  就在这里
Ah, yes. There it is.
还在这里
Still here.
鼻子画得不太像  但是
Well, the nose isn't quite right, but --
那是你吗
That's you?
是的  他们当我像圣人一样尊奉
Yeah. They venerated me a bit as a saint.
他们是白痴
They're idiots.
手杖在哪里
Where's the staff?
在楼上
It's upstairs.
那是正常的沃德还是更狂暴的沃德
Is that the normal Ward or the new, angrier Ward?
分辨不出
I can't tell.
好安静
It's quiet.
不然我怎么会放心地把秘密交给他们
Why do you think I trusted them with my secret?
因为他们发誓保守秘密
They take a vow of silence.
但当你逼他们说时
But when you get them talking...
他们会尖叫[告密]
they squeal.
如果你要战胜神
If you want to defeat a god,
你就必须成为神
you must become one.
我们得帮他
We need to help him!
我去追她
I'll get her.
他怎么样了
How is he?
我不知道该怎么做  他不是人类
I don't know what to do. He's not human.
他要死了
He's dying.
我们知道  但她不懂他的身体构造
We know, but she doesn't understand his anatomy.
-而我都...  -老天啊
- And I'm even w-- - What in god's name?
我的天呐
Oh, my god.
有时你必须站出来
Sometimes, you have to just jump in
把事情搞清楚
and figure things out.
阿斯加德人的再生能力比我们快
Now, Asgardians regenerate faster than we do.
也许我们尽可能维持他的生命
Maybe we can keep him alive long enough--
好让他的身体能自愈
For his body to heal itself.
那我现在要找什么
Okay, what am I looking for?
他的心脏
His heart.
救救我
Help me!
我好像找到了
Oh, okay. I think I got it.
-心脏  -好极了
- Heart. - Oh, yeah.
有没有撕破或是断裂
Can you feel a tear or rupture?
在他的心脏上施加压力  尽量放慢出血
Clamp down hard on his heart. Try to slow the bleeding.
格兰特  放下手杖
Grant, drop the staff.
离我远点
Get away from me.
-沃德特工  -你不是这样的
- Agent Ward. - This isn't you.
退后
Get back.
求求你  救救我
Please! Help me!
求求你
Please!
格兰特
Grant.
救救我
Help me!
求求你  救救我
Please, help me!
格兰特
Grant!
-还不行  格兰特  -救救我
- Not yet, Grant. - Help me!
-但是他要  -还不是时候
- But he's gonna-- - Not yet.
如果你抛下绳子  我就会把你也扔进去
Throw him the rope, and I'll throw you in there, too.
求求你
Please!
格兰特
Grant!
我的天呐  你还好吧
Oh, my god. Are you okay?
过来
Come here.
你在开玩笑吧
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
这次让我帮忙
This time, let me help.
来吧
Come on.
我一点也不怕你
I am not afraid of you.
我死了吗
Am I dead?
看来没有
Apparently not.
千年来  你无疑是我见过
You are easily the most beautiful thing I've seen
最漂亮的尤物
in a thousand years.
科尔森这么做了吗
Coulson did that?
他就这样把手塞进去了
He just shoved his hand inside?
他必须那样做  我僵住了  不知道该怎么做
Well, he had to. I froze, didn't know what to do.
你没僵住
Hey, you didn't freeze.
你只是不会
You just won't be up for the idea
把手伸进别人的胸腔里
put your hand inside somebody else's chest.
老妈老爸来电
也许我该站出来了
Maybe I should jump in.
是的
Yeah.
老爸
Hi, dad.
我也很高兴听到你的声音
Yeah, it's great to hear your voice, too.
我这几天一直想打电话给你
I've been meaning to call you for a couple of days.
这几周比较辛苦
It's been a difficult few weeks.
你拿着手杖的时候  看到什么了吗
When you held it, did you see anything?
那你是怎么做到的
Then how?
你怎么拿得了三个
How did you hold all three?
因为我每天都看到
Because I see it every day.
我见过这种神情
I know that look.
你动心了
You tempted?
你想看到的是什么
Now, what is it you want to see?
我们有很多相似之处
You and I have a lot in common.
我们都被刺中过心脏
We've both been stabbed in the heart.
我被杀死了
I was killed.
差不多算是
Well, almost.
我记不大清了
I'm hazy on that.
死后  一片空白
Afterwards... is kind of a blank.
没有被救活的记忆
I have no memory of being revived,
没有在医院的记忆
of being in a hospital.
只是在几个月后醒来了
Just...woke up a few months later.
你觉得很困扰吗  科尔森先生
And are you haunted by it, Mr. Coulson?
不觉得
No.
不算是
Not exactly.
那你纠结什么啊
Then what's the problem?
我想你说得对
I suppose you're right.
我们能送你回大学吗
Can we give you a lift back to the university?
欧洲现在对阿斯加德的事物
Well, you know, with Europe's new fascination
很是着迷
with all things Asgardian,
我在想是否该在别的地方重新开始了
I'm wondering if it's time to start over somewhere else.
美丽的海滩
Nice beach?
过喝热带饮料  做按摩的生活吗
Life of tropical drinks and massages?
我会觉得无聊的
Mm, oh, I'd get bored.
你该考虑美国西北地区
You should consider the American northwest.
也许是波兰
Maybe Portland.
那里有很多美食  交响乐团也很棒
Good food scene. Great philharmonic.
除非你会来探望我
Well, if you will come and visit.
我可不会和随便什么人都分享我的经历
It's not everyone I get to share my stories with.
行啊
Sure.
如果托尔刚好在  我会帮你引见
And if Thor's in town, I'll introduce you.
我能习惯夜床服务
I could get used to turndown service
和枕头上的几块薄荷糖
and little mints on my pillow.
通宵工作不常有
Overnights aren't standard.
我们该好好享受一夜
We deserve a nice night.
特别是你
You especially.
你感觉怎么样
How you feeling?
不大好
Not great.
对不起
I'm sorry.
因为之前的事
For before.
我
I'm...
我不是那个人
I'm not that guy.
当你救人性命时
When you're a guy who saves lives,
我能忽视些许"绿巨人的愤怒"
I can overlook a little Hulk rage.
没有伤害  就不算犯规
No harm, no foul.
你就让一切都随风而逝吗
Does everything just roll off your back?
不是
No.
如果这样有所帮助  我会一直生气
If it helped, I'd rage all the time,
但那样没有帮助
but it doesn't.
我看到的
What I saw...
是关于我弟弟的事
It was about my brother.
我猜到了
I figured.
我知道你不喜欢聊天
I know you're not one to talk,
但我说过  我在你身边
but, like I said, I'm here.
可以借你个肩膀
My shoulder's free.
我累坏了
I'm beat.
也许下次吧
Another time, maybe.
你知道我在哪里
Well, you know where I live.
漫威《神盾局特工》
"Marvel's agents of S.H.I.E.L.D."
很快回来
will return in a moment.
我睡着了吗
Did I fall asleep?
睡了一小会儿
For a little while.
但是  那样很好
But, uh, that's good.
说明你放松了
It means you are relaxed.
我的感觉正是如此  放松
That's precisely how I'm feeling -- relaxed.
老实说  塔希提岛太过美好  简直让人难以置信
Honestly, Tahiti's too good to be true.
我知道
I know.
这是个神奇的地方
It's a magical place.